Welcome back.
In this video, we will discuss ecommerce analytics.
So far, you have built your data model in Power BI, created metrics for customers
and orders, and understood the business goals, such as cross-selling and upselling.
Whiskique's management wants you to dive deep into quantity upsell strategies.
This particular strategy increases sales and saves on shipping costs.
You aim to build dashboard-style pages to present shipping costs by region and product.
You will also build a what-if analysis dashboard-style page to present
the impact of shipping higher product quantities on sales and profitability.
Whiskique hasn't automated integration with shipping
providers and does not capture shipping costs at the transaction level.
Monitoring shipping costs remain a focus for the management.
Let us look at a fictitious example of shipping a glass jar of spices from California to Texas.
The cost of shipping an individual jar is $10.
Suppose you were to ship a crate with nine spices; the package dimensions and the total weight increase.
The shipment now costs $45 or $5 per jar for nine jars.
The per unit cost went down as the quantity increased.
These savings can be passed on to the business as extra profit or to the customers as extra savings.
Besides, this is great for the environment — a win-win solution for everyone.
Whiskique's management wants to implement a similar strategy for their pet food business.
In a what-if analysis, you empower users to visualize the impact
of changing parameter values—for example, average shipped quantity.
Users can see the impact on business operations when combined with interactive filters.
The management can view the shipping cost savings at the individual product level and
across the entire business using the what-if analysis dashboard-style page you will build.
As you build your dashboard-style pages, the following data visualization
guidelines will help you structure your pages and effectively communicate insights.
Add appropriate page and chart titles that answer the goal of a dashboard and that of each chart.
Display key KPIs, for example, sales and shipping cost savings, in large numbers.
And finally, Interactivity using parameters and filters improves user engagement and invokes follow-up questions.
Let us now start building our what-if analysis dashboard-style page.